

💌 DruSerkes@gmail.com 🚱 druserkes 📞 203-912-2047 👂 New York, NY 🛭 in dru-serkes 🗘 druserkes

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software engineer with experience using Javascript and Python to craft creative solutions. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes in both one-on-one and group settings.

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, TypeScript

LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jasmine, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: Git, PostgreSQL, Axios, Jinja, VSCode, Heroku, Netlify

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration, Attention to detail, Initiative, Time Management, Handling Pressure

### **PROJECTS**

Lyrify 2020

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- Crafted a responsive single-page app with React, Redux, and Material UI components working with a Node / Express backend
- Followed Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify and consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL
- · Improved custom search feature by validating and cleaning user inputs to increase rate of positive results

Quote Me 2020

Quote generator

- Built and tested a responsive single page app with a combination of React, Typescript, Jest, and Styled Components.
- Consumed a 3rd party API to provide users access to randomly generated quotes they could then copy or Tweet

The Easy Meal 2020

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- Built Flask Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates, and a UI responsively styled with bootstrap and custom CSS
- Secured against CSRF with form validation, and applied bcrypt authentication for user registration and login
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes, and cached recipe data with PostgreSQL to reduce API calls.
- Implemented asynchronous search with JavaScript (Axios, jQuery)

Jobly 2020

Mock job-seeking website

- Developed a RESTful API with Node / Express, and a modular UI for this single page React app
- · Built and validated forms with Formik and JSONSchema, and managed data with PostgreSQL
- Followed JWT standard for user authentication and authorization

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track
Student

April 2020 - Current

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material
- 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
- Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects
- · Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

Jersey Boys August 2015 - Current

Actor · New York, NY

- Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show
- Understudied and carried out the duties of 6 different roles, going on as late as mid-show
- Took action to save 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

King School

January 2020 - March 2020

 ${\sf Acting\ Coach\cdot Stamford,\ CT}$ 

- Advised on best practices for pursuing professional careers in the entertainment industry
- Offered young professionals modern methods for approaching new and current material
- Engaged with students of all experience levels one-on-one, producing greater understanding and depth of performance

# **EDUCATION**

Springboard 2020 Software Engineering Career Track Certification Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient